<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixeds on </title>
    <link>/Hippocamplus/fixed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixeds on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/Hippocamplus/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CPP</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/cpp/</guid>
      <description>Resources File I/O Read text file one line at a time  Data structures String manipulation Split a string    Resources  C++ Core Guidelines C++ Primer (5th Edition). Stanley B. Lippman, Josée Lajoie, Barbara E. Moo Accelerated C++. Andrew Koenig  Slides:
 The Spirit of C++ Back To Basics: Modern C++ Style   File I/O Read text file one line at a time #include &amp;lt;fstream&amp;gt; std::ifstream in_file(&amp;#39;file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/emacs/</guid>
      <description>Basic configuration General commands Kill ring Calculator Console-size split screen  MELPA package repository Solarized theme For R Emacs Speaks Statistics Auto-complete Smart underscores Poly-mode for R + Markdown Custom keyboard shortcuts  For writing Spell checking Thesaurus and synonyms Grammar checking  For LaTeX Word count Chunk folding  For Markdown Table formatting Markdown live preview  For Python Elpy python mode Send commands to a specific buffer  For C/CPP Tags  For Shell For WDL workflows For file manipulation Compare two files (diff) CSV/TSV Dired mode  For Version Control File encryption On HPCs For online notes Evernote Simplenote  For OSX Maximize window at opening Keybindings Ispell Explicit path definition    I use Emacs for almost everything: coding, writing, taking notes, managing tasks, using version control, preparing presentations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/expression/</guid>
      <description>Writing General Starting the sentence Explanation Not sure Opening Nice expression/style Introduce the second part of a sentence  Introduction/reviews Intro the intro Pionner work Changing subject More Closing  Discussion  Oral Expression Advices    Writing Some recommendations from Sportscience:
 i.e. and e.g. only within parenthesis (is that a thing?) aim for economy. However or synonyms at most once per paragraph. while/since for time related stuff, not instead of whereas/although/because.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/latex/</guid>
      <description>Cheatsheets Standard packages TinyTeX Misc Document class Page size Font sizes Change the symbol in lists Math calligraphy Languages and encoding Links Table of contents Metadata  Figures Position Sub-figures Supplementary figures  Tables Control tabular width Add vertical padding Supplementary tables Spanning columns/rows Align columns Rectangular selection/cut/paste Tables from R  Code blocks For manuscripts Abstract Author affiliation Text formatting Notes/comments Main text and supplements in two documents Compare versions and highlight revisions One figure = one file  Bibliography Reduce long list of authors “Name Year” style Order of initials No URL or DOI  Presentations Changing the font Section slides Themes Background image Backup slides Link to frame    A lot of good information in the LaTeX Wikibook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/markdown/</guid>
      <description>Tips Converting Markdown into nice HTML pages Converting Markdown into slides Jekyll websites Themes Table of Contents Math formulas  blogdown websites Themes Table of Contents Draft posts Math formulas Bibliography  R Markdown   Tips  / to add some vertical space/break (e.g. in slides). Use two ` and a space to escape ` in inline code. E.g `` `pwd` `` gives `pwd`. --- to add horizontal line/separation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math/Stats</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/math/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/math/stats/</guid>
      <description>Probability distributions Binomial Hypergeometric Normal Poisson Beta-binomial Beta  Statistical tests Student t-test Fisher’s exact test \(\chi^2\) test Wilcoxon test ANOVA  Regression &amp;amp; Machine Learning Linear regression LASSO LOESS Machine Learning basics CART Neural Networks SVM  Misc stats Markov Model Monte Carlo methods MCMC Hidden Markov Model Maximum Likelihood Estimation Expectation-Maximization Greedy algorithm Bayesian vs Frequentist FM-index  Graph theory De Bruijn graphs Hamiltonian path Euclidian path  Algebra SVD decomposition PCA    All of this is mostly extracted from Wikipedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org mode</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/org-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/org-mode/</guid>
      <description>Org file Configuration Syntax Keybindings From anywhere Edit mode Timestamps Repeating events Agenda views Capture  TODO entry Tables Code block Property drawer Habits entry Links Tags Clocking time Custom agenda views To check next   I’m giving Org mode a try. This page will contain my configuration and the small subset of commands that I want to learn.
 Org Manual Org Mode - Organize Your Life In Plain Text!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/python/</guid>
      <description>Naming and formatting Objects Array Hash Class String Function  Input/Output Module, files, imports Packaging code Install a module locally  Passing arguments to a script Graphs Shell integration Timing Bioinfo Sequences Fasta SAM files VCF  Tricks Jupyter notebooks   Some notes on my recent attempt to learn Python.
Naming and formatting  Use lowercase _-separated for modules and functions name. E.g. my_function. Use CapsWord for classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/r/</guid>
      <description>Details to remember Order in condition assessment  Read files in chunk Graphs Palette with many colors ggplot2 tricks Multi-panel ggplots Change font in ggplot2 Waffle graphs  Rmarkdown Zoom-on-click images Beamer presentation Jekyll website  data.table package Rcpp Linux setup    What They Forgot to Teach You About R  Details to remember  Use rbindlist from data.table package for a memory-optimized and faster do.call(rbind, list(.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/shell/</guid>
      <description>External links GNU screen .bashrc aliases Misc Colors in less Avoid killing ssh jobs Custom prompt  One-liners Bash &amp;amp; Pipes AWK Perl one-liners  Shell scripting Variables Looping If Then Else  Modules Ubuntu Sound problems  OSX Mount server Setup WD Elements external hard drive    This page focuses on configuration of the terminal, one-liners and scripting. Command-line tools I used (e.g. git, snakemake, docker) are described in the Tools page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/tools/</guid>
      <description>Git Snakemake jq vd rsync Docker WDL Makefile FTP For file conversion Misc PDF    Git  Commit all modification and added files: git commit -am &#34;informative message&#34; To show all the history of a file: git log -p -- file To retrieve a specific version of a file: git show COMMIT:file Revert repo to a specific commit: git checkout COMMIT Undo a commit: git reset HEAD~ and then for the real commit git commit -c ORIG_HEAD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/internet/</guid>
      <description>Misc tools DuckDuckGo Ubuntu Sync a specific Google Drive folder on Ubuntu Sync PDFs between Mendeley and Google Drive Zotero Dowload files from Dropbox Record a webradio stream with VLC   Misc tools  https://www.diagrams.net/ to make cartoon and diagrams (used to be draw.io) MS Paint Online   DuckDuckGo DuckDuckGo is a “search engine that doesn’t track you”. It provides nice “bangs” to search directly specific websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/Hippocamplus/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Hippocamplus/about/</guid>
      <description>About this website This is where I put all the useful information I keep on forgetting. Instead of googling the same things over and over, wasting time and server energy I put them here. It’s like a second memory, better than my hippocampus, my hippocamPLUS…
 About me  Personal page with links. Twitter.  My current lab  Computational Genomics Lab at UCSC. Genomics Institute at UCSC   My previous labs  Bourque Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>