<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixeds on </title>
    <link>/fixed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixeds on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CPP</title>
      <link>/cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cpp/</guid>
      <description>Resources File I/O  Read text file one line at a time  Data structures String manipulation  Split a string    Resources  C++ Core Guidelines C++ Primer (5th Edition). Stanley B. Lippman, Josée Lajoie, Barbara E. Moo Accelerated C++. Andrew Koenig  Slides:
 The Spirit of C++ Back To Basics: Modern C++ Style   File I/O Read text file one line at a time #include &amp;lt;fstream&amp;gt; std::ifstream in_file(&amp;#39;file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs</title>
      <link>/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/emacs/</guid>
      <description>Basic configuration General commands  Kill ring Calculator Console-size split screen  MELPA package repository Solarized theme For R  Emacs Speaks Statistics Auto-complete Smart underscores Poly-mode for R + Markdown Custom keyboard shortcuts Jumping to function definitions  For writing  Spell checking Thesaurus and synonyms Grammar checking  For LaTeX  Word count Chunk folding  For Markdown  Table formatting Markdown live preview  For Python  Elpy python mode Send commands to a specific buffer  For C/CPP  Tags  For Shell For WDL workflows For file manipulation  Compare two files (diff) CSV/TSV Dired mode  For Version Control File encryption On HPCs For online notes  Evernote Simplenote  For OSX  Maximize window at opening Keybindings Ispell Explicit path definition    I use Emacs for almost everything: coding, writing, taking notes, managing tasks, using version control, preparing presentations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression</title>
      <link>/expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expression/</guid>
      <description>Writing  Grammarly lessons Synonyms General  Starting the sentence Explanation Not sure Opening Nice expression/style Introduce the second part of a sentence  Introduction/reviews  Intro the intro Pionner work Changing subject More Closing  Discussion  Oral Expression  Advices    Writing Some recommendations from Sportscience:
 i.e. and e.g. only within parenthesis (is that a thing?) aim for economy. However or synonyms at most once per paragraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX</title>
      <link>/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/latex/</guid>
      <description>Cheatsheets Standard packages TinyTeX Misc  Document class Page size Font sizes and style Change the symbol in lists Math calligraphy Languages and encoding Links Table of contents Metadata  Figures  Position Sub-figures Supplementary figures  Tables  Control tabular width Add vertical padding Supplementary tables Spanning columns/rows Align columns Rectangular selection/cut/paste Tables from R  Code blocks For manuscripts  Abstract Author affiliation Text formatting Notes/comments using the todo package Main text and supplements in two documents Compare versions and highlight revisions One figure = one file  Bibliography  Reduce long list of authors “Name Year” style Order of initials No URL or DOI  Presentations  Changing the font Section slides Themes Aspect ratio Background image Backup slides Link to frame    A lot of good information in the LaTeX Wikibook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/markdown/</guid>
      <description>Markdown tips YAML header Bibliography Markdown to PDF report  Custom document header Comments Custom tables  Markdown to Word document Markdown to HTML pages Markdown to slides  PDF slides HTML slides  Websites  blogdown websites Jekyll websites (deprecated)  R Markdown   I compile markdown documents using the RMarkdown R package (which uses Pandoc).
Rscript -e &amp;#39;rmarkdown::render(&amp;quot;document.md&amp;quot;)&amp;#39; The output format is either defined in the YAML header (see below), or can be specified with output_format=.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math/Stats</title>
      <link>/math/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/math/stats/</guid>
      <description>Probability distributions  Binomial Hypergeometric Normal Poisson Beta-binomial Beta  Statistical tests  Student t-test Fisher’s exact test \(\chi^2\) test Wilcoxon test ANOVA  Regression &amp;amp; Machine Learning  Linear regression LASSO LOESS Machine Learning basics CART Neural Networks SVM  Misc stats  Markov Model Monte Carlo methods MCMC Hidden Markov Model Maximum Likelihood Estimation Expectation-Maximization Greedy algorithm Bayesian vs Frequentist FM-index  Graph theory  De Bruijn graphs Hamiltonian path Euclidian path  Algebra  SVD decomposition PCA    All of this is mostly extracted from Wikipedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org mode</title>
      <link>/org-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/org-mode/</guid>
      <description>Org file Configuration Syntax Keybindings  From anywhere Edit mode Timestamps Repeating events Agenda views Calendar view with calfw Capture  TODO entry Tables Code block Property drawer Habits entry Links Tags Clocking time Custom agenda views Custom holidays Shift timestamps by X hours when traveling to a different time zone Reverse the order of headers To check next  Termux sync with git Orgzly to interact with org files    I’m giving Org mode a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/python/</guid>
      <description>Input/Output Passing arguments to a script Objects  Array/lists Hash Set Class String Function Data frame (pandas)  Multi-threading Naming and formatting Module, files, imports  Packaging code Install a module locally  Graphs Shell integration  Run commands with subprocess  Resource monitoring Bioinfo  Sequences Fasta SAM files VCF  Tricks Jupyter notebooks   Some notes on my recent attempt to learn Python.
Input/Output To read the standard input:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/r/</guid>
      <description>Details to remember  Order in condition assessment  Read files in chunk Graphs  Palette with many colors ggplot2 tricks Multi-panel ggplots Change font in ggplot2 Waffle graphs Gantt charts  Rmarkdown  Zoom-on-click images Beamer presentation Jekyll website  data.table package Rcpp Linux setup    What They Forgot to Teach You About R  Details to remember  Use rbindlist from data.table package for a memory-optimized and faster do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell</title>
      <link>/shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shell/</guid>
      <description>External links GNU screen .bashrc aliases Misc  Colors in less Avoid killing ssh jobs Custom prompt  One-liners  Bash &amp;amp; Pipes AWK Perl one-liners  Shell scripting  Variables Looping If Then Else  Modules Ubuntu  Sound problems  OSX  Mount server Setup WD Elements external hard drive    This page focuses on configuration of the terminal, one-liners and scripting. Command-line tools I used (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/</guid>
      <description>Git Snakemake bcftools jq vd rsync Docker WDL Makefile FTP For file conversion  Misc PDF    Git  Commit all modification and added files: git commit -am &#34;informative message&#34; To show all the history of a file: git log -p -- file To retrieve a specific version of a file: git show COMMIT:file Revert repo to a specific commit: git checkout COMMIT Undo a commit: git reset HEAD~ and then for the real commit git commit -c ORIG_HEAD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS/Internet</title>
      <link>/os/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/internet/</guid>
      <description>Misc tools DuckDuckGo Ubuntu  Update expired keys (French) Accents in Gnome Ubuntu  Change the CTRL-. binding in Ubuntu 22.04 Install a specific/older R version Sync a specific folder on Ubuntu  On the cloud Sync in real time with Syncthing [DEPRECATED?] Before: sync a specific Google Drive folder on Ubuntu  Zotero  [DEPRECATED] Before: sync PDFs between Mendeley and Google Drive  Dowload files from Dropbox Record a webradio stream with VLC   Misc tools  https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About this website This is where I put all the useful information I keep on forgetting. Instead of googling the same things over and over, wasting time and server energy I put them here. It’s like a second memory, better than my hippocampus, my hippocamPLUS…
 About me  Personal page with links. Twitter.  My current lab  Computational Genomics Lab at UCSC. Genomics Institute at UCSC   My previous labs  Bourque Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>